<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects | Mouna Belaid</title>
    <link>https://mounabelaid.netlify.app/project/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://mounabelaid.netlify.app/project/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Projects</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© Mouna Belaid, 2023</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://mounabelaid.netlify.app/img/icon-192.png</url>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>https://mounabelaid.netlify.app/project/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>git-github RStudio Cheatsheet</title>
      <link>https://mounabelaid.netlify.app/project/gitgithubcheatsheet/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mounabelaid.netlify.app/project/gitgithubcheatsheet/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I was happy to make a contribution of a new cheatsheet in support of &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.rstudio.com/&#34;&gt;RStudio&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/rstudio/cheatsheets/blob/main/git-github.pdf&#34;&gt;cheatsheet&lt;/a&gt; covers the use of Git and GitHub in RStudio.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many high quality cheatsheets on R topics have been generously contributed by R users and are available &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.rstudio.com/resources/cheatsheets/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some cheatsheets are also available in the RStudio IDE under Help &amp;gt; Cheatsheets&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You may visit the Cheatsheet GitHub Repository by following this &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/rstudio/cheatsheets&#34;&gt;link&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you would like to contribute a new cheatsheet, you may follow the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/rstudio/cheatsheets/blob/main/.github/CONTRIBUTING.md&#34;&gt;contributing guidelines&lt;/a&gt; which provide a useful starting place.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s also possible to contribute to this effort by translating the available cheatsheets into many languages e.g. French, Arabic, Italian, Chinese, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Installation of R</title>
      <link>https://mounabelaid.netlify.app/project/installationofr/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mounabelaid.netlify.app/project/installationofr/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Throughout &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=oaEhlJ2c94g&#34;&gt;this video&lt;/a&gt;, I will show you what are the instructions to follow in order to install the &lt;a href=&#34;https://cran.r-project.org/&#34;&gt;R software&lt;/a&gt; on your machine.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Installation of RStudio</title>
      <link>https://mounabelaid.netlify.app/project/installationofrstudio/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mounabelaid.netlify.app/project/installationofrstudio/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Throughout &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=4l45_Mbm_T0&#34;&gt;this video&lt;/a&gt;, I will show you what are the instructions to follow in order to install &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.rstudio.com/products/rstudio/download/&#34;&gt;RStudio&lt;/a&gt; on your machine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;RStudio is a free, open-source, cross-platform development environment for R software.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Personal website</title>
      <link>https://mounabelaid.netlify.app/project/personalwebsite/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mounabelaid.netlify.app/project/personalwebsite/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have used the blogdown R package in order to create my personal website. I really recommend this incredible R package for creating websites using RMarkdown and Hugo.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>covid19tunisia R package</title>
      <link>https://mounabelaid.netlify.app/project/covid19tunisia/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mounabelaid.netlify.app/project/covid19tunisia/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/MounaBelaid/covid19tunisia&#34;&gt;covid19tunisia&lt;/a&gt; is the package that I have recently built in the programming language R.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The work I did is part of covid19R project that provides a single package that allows users to access all of the tidy COVID19 datasets collected by data packages (covid19nytimes_states, covid19nytimes_counties, covid19france, CanadaC19_cases, covid19us and recently mine was added) that implement the covid19R tidy data standard. To learn more about the Covid19R project, please check out &lt;a href=&#34;https://covid19r.github.io/documentation/&#34;&gt;this documentation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m very pleased to live such an experience and work on such an open source project that allows me to improve my skills on things worth doing. In fact, from the start of coronavirus spread in &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tunisia&#34;&gt;Tunisia&lt;/a&gt;, I have been collecting daily data from the official sources that I explored by creating a &lt;a href=&#34;https://mounabelaid.shinyapps.io/coronavirus/&#34;&gt;shiny application&lt;/a&gt;. After getting to know this project, I feel like it would be really great if I could explore more this data collected and share it with the R community.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tracking Coronavirus COVID-19 in Tunisia</title>
      <link>https://mounabelaid.netlify.app/project/coronavirus/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mounabelaid.netlify.app/project/coronavirus/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As the COVID_19 outbreak continues to evolve worldwide and particularly in my country &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tunisia&#34;&gt;Tunisia&lt;/a&gt;, I have created an application using RShiny tracking the situation of coronavirus spread in Tunisia. Please follow &lt;a href=&#34;https://mounabelaid.shinyapps.io/coronavirus/&#34;&gt;this link&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Twitter Sentiment Analysis of news from American profiles</title>
      <link>https://mounabelaid.netlify.app/project/twittersentimentanalysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mounabelaid.netlify.app/project/twittersentimentanalysis/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In &lt;a href=&#34;https://mounabelaid.shinyapps.io/twittersentimentanalysis/&#34;&gt;this application&lt;/a&gt;, the user would be able to extract data from Twitter. I focus the work on American twitter profiles :&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Hill&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;strong&gt;Reuters Top News&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;strong&gt;Sky News&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;strong&gt;BBC News (World)&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;The New York Times&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;strong&gt;CNN International&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;strong&gt;HuffPost&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;strong&gt;Fox News&lt;/strong&gt; -
&lt;strong&gt;CNBC&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I resort to text mining in order to create a wordcloud which shows the most frequented words used in the last 100 tweets. The tweets would be cleaned before the display of the wordcloud. The user may change the number of tweets extracted using the radio button. Morever, I perform a sentiment analysis of textual contents of twitter posts by using the categories identified as anger, anticipation, disgust, fear, joy, negative, positive, sadness, surprise and trust. It would be possible to download the barplot.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Brain Drain reasons analysis, Text Mining in Sociology</title>
      <link>https://mounabelaid.netlify.app/project/braindrain/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mounabelaid.netlify.app/project/braindrain/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;https://drive.google.com/file/d/1HiUm8a4vPK61Sc2kzC0T25psf-y9Nk8C/view?usp=drive_open&#34;&gt;project&lt;/a&gt; is about Brain Drain in Tunisia. A survey was conducted among
Tunisian people in order to get answers of several questions about this topic. As a team, we are
mainly interested in making analysis about two basic questions among all the questions being answered:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;✦ What are the reasons that would push you to leave Tunisia?
✦ Socially, what’s the difference between Tunisia and abroad in social life?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The text mining project pipeline is as follow:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Read questionnaire data from a csv file&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Initialize raw corpus&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Text cleaning&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Text representation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Topic modeling&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Clustering&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Predictive modeling&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Visualization and interpretation of final results&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We resort technically to the programming language Python.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Create your wordcloud</title>
      <link>https://mounabelaid.netlify.app/project/wordcloud/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mounabelaid.netlify.app/project/wordcloud/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is &lt;a href=&#34;https://mounabelaid.shinyapps.io/application/&#34;&gt;the first Shiny application&lt;/a&gt; that I&amp;rsquo;ve created. It’s powered by R software. You just need a text to copy and paste in the box then to click on the run button in order to create a wordcloud and obtain a table in a dynamic format that shows every word in the text and its frequency and don’t worry the text will be cleaned before displaying the wordcloud. That means punctuation and stopwords would be removed automatically. You can download the plot and save it as well. Don’t hesitate to give it a try!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Analyzing Donald Trump inauguration speech</title>
      <link>https://mounabelaid.netlify.app/project/donaldtrumpspeech/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mounabelaid.netlify.app/project/donaldtrumpspeech/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;❝ January 20th, 2017 will be remerbered as the day the people became the rules of this nation again ❞ said Donald Trump. It was an unforgetable day for all the american people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this regard, I got the idea of analyzing the Donald Trump inauguration speech and I could not find a better software than R to obtain good results. I resort to Data Mining in order to create a wordcloud which resumes the main words said by the 45th President of the United States. Data Mining is one of the interesting techniques of exploring data. &lt;a href=&#34;https://rpubs.com/mounabelaid/243878&#34;&gt;See project&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
